9news.com.au 2015-06-22

# Privacy Policy

Last Updated: 2 June 2015 

### Privacy Policy

Ninemsn Pty Ltd ( **NINEMSN** ) understands that privacy is important to our users, business contacts, employees and people who feature in content on our network. At NINEMSN we are committed to protecting and maintaining your privacy. NINEMSN is bound by the Australian Privacy Principles ( **APPs** ), which are contained in the Privacy Act 1988 ( **Privacy Act** ). As part of our business operations we may collect your personal information. This Privacy Policy describes the type of personal information we may collect and how we use, store and disclose this personal information. If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please contact our Privacy Officer (using the contact details below). 

As part of NINEMSN’S normal business operations we may collect your personal information. This Privacy Policy describes the type of personal information that NINEMSN may collect and how we use, store and disclose this personal information. It applies to your conduct on the NINEMSN network, which includes the online websites and mobile sites bearing the NINEMSN header and footer, as well as downloadable apps (the " **NINEMSN Network** ").

This Privacy Policy is in addition to the general Terms of Use governing the NINEMSN Network and should be read in conjunction with such [Terms of Use.](http://advertising.ninemsn.com.au/article.aspx?id=8363139)

As a media organisation, NINEMSN's handling of personal information in the course of its journalism activities is governed by the Australian Press Council’s Privacy Standards (as discussed below and attached to this Privacy Policy as Annexure A).

### Microsoft Products and Services

The NINEMSN Network allows users to access leading global Microsoft products and services such as Outlook, Skype, Xbox, Bing and Windows Live (“ **Microsoft Products** ”). Personal information provided by you in connection with Microsoft Products may be collected and used by NINEMSN (in which case this Privacy Policy will govern our use and collection of your personal information) and Microsoft Corporation (and its affiliates) (in which case the [Microsoft Online Privacy Statement](http://go.microsoft.com/fwlink/?LinkId=74170) will apply to Microsoft’s collection and use of your personal information).

### NINEMSN AND PRIVACY

### NINEMSN’s Commitment to Privacy

When you deal with NINEMSN, whether online or otherwise, NINEMSN takes its privacy obligations seriously. Generally, NINEMSN will handle personal information collected online consistently with the way that it handles personal information collected offline.

This Privacy Policy is designed to tell you about how NINEMSN uses and manages personal information provided to, or collected by NINEMSN. We believe you should be made aware of our practices so you can make informed decisions about how you allow us to use your personal information.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

In this ever changing world NINEMSN may, from time to time, review and update this Privacy Policy to take account of new laws, technologies and changes to NINEMSN’s operations. All personal information held by NINEMSN will be governed by NINEMSN's most recent Privacy Policy. The most recent Privacy Policy will always be available on our website or by contacting the NINEMSN Privacy Officer (contact details set out below).

### WHAT KIND OF PERSONAL INFORMATION DOES NINEMSN COLLECT AND HOW DOES NINEMSN COLLECT IT?

### The type of information we collect

The types of personal information we collect will vary depending on the nature of your dealings with NINEMSN and the NINEMSN Network. We only collect personal information that we need for our business activities, or which is volunteered to us. In general, the type of personal information NINEMSN collects and holds could include (but is not limited to) your name, address (postal and email), contact details, geographic location (including your suburb or post code), gender, date of birth, transaction details relating to your use of NINEMSN and/or Microsoft products and services and any preferences you tell us about.

### How we collect your information

We may collect your personal information over the internet, over the phone, when you write to us, when you attend an event run by us or when you participate in a survey, questionnaire, competition or other marketing campaign run by us or our partners.

In order to access some NINEMSN services and products, you will be asked to sign in with an e-mail address and password, which we refer to as your Mi9 ID credentials. Currently, this may be done using your log-in details to third party social networking services such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn or Skype, or via your Windows Live ID. You can use your Mi9 ID credentials to sign in to many different NINEMSN services, websites and products, as well as those of select NINEMSN partners. By signing in on one NINEMSN website, product or service, you may be automatically signed into other NINEMSN websites, products and services that use Mi9 IDs. As part of creating your credentials, you may also be requested to provide questions and secret answers, which we use to help verify your identity and assist in resetting your password, as well as an alternate e-mail address. Some services may require added security, and in these cases, you may be asked to create an additional security key. 

### How we store your personal information

NINEMSN may hold your personal information in electronic or hard copy format or a combination of both. This personal information may be combined or linked with other information held about you, including information that we receive from third parties. We have taken a number of physical, electronic and procedural steps to protect your personal information from misuse, interference, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure.

NINEMSN protects the personal information it collects in a secure database stored by our third party data storage provider. It is in proprietary data format, which can only be read using proprietary tools.

NINEMSN also employs firewalls, intrusion detection systems and virus scanning tools to protect against unauthorised persons and viruses from entering our systems.

NINEMSN employees are required, as a condition of their employment, to treat personal information held by NINEMSN as confidential, and to maintain the confidentiality of that personal information. They are also required to undertake training about privacy compliance and how to manage personal information.

### Collection of information which is not ‘Personal Information’

We also collect additional information about your interaction with the NINEMSN Network websites, services and products (including the Microsoft Products) without identifying you as an individual. For example, we use website analytics tools on our websites to retrieve information from your browser, including the website you came from, the search engine(s) and the keywords you used to find our site, the pages you view within our site, your browser add-ons, and your browser's width and height. We also use technologies, such as cookies and web beacons (described below), to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on our sites and services. Additionally, we receive certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring Web site addresses. We also deliver advertisements (see the **Display of Advertising** section below) and provide website analytics tools on non-NINEMSN and Microsoft websites and services, and we collect information such as page views on these third party sites as well.

Anonymous data which we collect about you via your interaction with the NINEMSN Network and these third party sites (where we provide website analytics tools or deliver advertisements) may be used by NINEMSN for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy or may be sold or otherwise provided by us to third parties including our partners, clients and service providers for purposes including (but not limited to) data-matching, campaign analysis, selling aggregated anonymous data via advertising exchanges, conducting launch surveys, and modelling. 

When you receive newsletters or promotional e-mails from NINEMSN, we may use web beacons (described below), customised links or similar technologies to determine whether the e-mail has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you with more focused e-mail communications or other information.

### ANONYMOUS TRANSACTIONS

NINEMSN will not make it mandatory for you to provide Personal Information unless such Personal Information is necessary in order for NINEMSN to provide a product/service or otherwise achieve the desired outcome. NINEMSN may however request that you provide Personal Information voluntarily to NINEMSN (for example, as part of a competition or questionnaire).

NINEMSN will allow you to transact with it anonymously wherever that is reasonable and practicable.

### Information we collect from other sources

In order to offer you a more consistent and personalised experience in your interactions with NINEMSN, information collected through one NINEMSN service may be combined with information obtained through other NINEMSN services. We may access information about you from our Related Bodies Corporate and third-party sources and platforms (such as social networking sites, databases, online marketing companies, Microsoft Products, third party websites on the NINEMSN Network (such as Daily Mail Australia websites) and ad targeting companies) and supplement the information we collect with information obtained from those third party sources. For example: 

  * we may use services from other companies that enable us to derive a general geographic area based on your IP address in order to customise certain services to your geographic area.
  * we may collect anonymous information provided to Microsoft through your Windows Live ID account;
  * if you connect your third-party social networking service profile (such as Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter or Windows Live) to the NINEMSN Network, we may access and use your username, profile image, location information, interests, activities, ‘likes’, connection list and age for those services; and
  * we may obtain third party information relating to your advertisement interaction and viewing data, such as ad click-through rates and information about how many times you viewed a particular advertisement.

To customise your user experience on the NINEMSN Network we provide you with the opportunity to connect, access and/or interact with third-party social networking services, such as Facebook and Twitter. When you connect to the NINEMSN Network through these social networking services, you will be able to see the social sharing habits of your friends and connections and participate seamlessly in our social capabilities, including commenting, live blogging, reactions, ratings, gaming mechanics and sharing content. You can connect the NINEMSN Network to your third party social networking service by downloading an application and logging into the application each time you return to the NINEMSN Network. By connecting to the NINEMSN Network through these third-party social networking services, you are authorising NINEMSN to access and use certain information from your social network profile. You can opt-out of authorising NINEMSN from collecting or access your information when you are not using the application and/or posting status updates, photographs and links to your social networking service profile on your behalf. Of course, you can cancel this service at any time by deleting the application from your social network account.

### HOW NINEMSN USES PERSONAL INFORMATION

Generally, we only use personal information for the primary purpose for which we have collected it, or for another closely related secondary purpose. For example, if you provide us with your personal information in order to enter a competition promoted on the NINEMSN Network, we will use this personal information for the purpose of facilitating the competition and for related secondary purposes only. Our potential usages of personal information which NINEMSN collects (and for which you consent to us using your personal information for) may include the following purposes: 

  * operating and improving our websites, products and services
  * providing you with news and information about our products and services (including newsletters, product surveys and special offers);
  * providing you with more effective customer service;
  * enabling us to conduct customer research; 
  * making the websites, services or products that form part of the NINEMSN Network easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information; 
  * performing research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services and technologies; 
  * displaying content and advertising that are customised to your interests, preferences and experiences. 
  * occasionally sending marketing and promotional material about our products and/or services (or the products and/or services of our Related Bodies Corporate) that we believe you may be interested in.
  * providing to entities whom NINEMSN or its Related Bodies Corporates have a shareholding in (“ **Associated Entities** ”) for the purpose of such entities providing data matching and targeted advertising services;
  * conducting competitions or promotions on behalf of NINEMSN and selected third parties; 
  * verifying your identity; 
  * to allow you to log in or otherwise access products and/or services owned by NINEMSN or its Related Bodies Corporate;
  * communicating with you, including by email, mail or telephone.
  * investigating any complaints about or made by you, or if we have reason to suspect that you are in breach of any of our Terms of Use or that you are or have been otherwise engaged in any unlawful activity; and/or
  * using personal information as otherwise required or permitted by any law (including the Privacy Act).

NINEMSN may state a more specific purpose at the point we collect your personal information. 

**_You acknowledge and agree that any personal information submitted by you on the NINEMSN Network may be provided by ninemsn to its Related Bodies Corporate (including but not limited to Nine Network Australia) and Associated Entities (defined above) and used by those organisations for any of the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Policy._**

Please contact the NINEMSN Privacy Officer via email at [privacyofficer@mi9.com.au](mailto:privacyofficer@mi9.com.au) if you wish to request that NINEMSN (or any of its Related Bodies Corporate) cease using your personal information for any or all of the purposes described under this Privacy Policy.

### DOES NINEMSN DISCLOSE PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES?

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, NINEMSN will not disclose your personal information outside of NINEMSN and its Related Bodies Corporate (including Nine Entertainment Co and Nine Network Australia Pty Limited) and Associated Entities without your consent.

NINEMSN may disclose personal information it collects about you to third parties for a variety of purposes in connection with NINEMSN providing its products, services and special offers to you (including to our agents, Related Bodies Corporate, Associated Entities and contractors). Personal information may be disclosed to third parties by NINEMSN in the following circumstances: 

  1. _Service Providers_

We occasionally engage other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, data-matching, providing customer support, hosting websites, providing debt recovery services, processing transactions, facilitating the connection of your third-party social networking service profile with the NINEMSN Network or performing statistical analysis of our services. Personal information collected by NINEMSN may be disclosed to these third parties to whom NINEMSN contracts out specialised functions. For example, NINEMSN may disclose your personal information to a business that provides competition management services to NINEMSN where that business needs your personal information to contact you in connection with your participation in the competition. If NINEMSN does need to disclose personal information to third party contractors under outsourcing or contracting arrangements, NINEMSN's policy is to take reasonable steps to ensure that those third parties: 

    1. comply with the APPs when they handle your personal information;
    2. preserve the confidentiality of the personal information; and
    3. are authorised only to use personal information in order to provide the services or to perform the functions required by NINEMSN.
  2. _Clients/Partners of NINEMSN_

In addition to disclosures of the personal information you submit on the NINEMSN Network you agree to elsewhere in the privacy policy (including those described above in **How NINEMSN Uses Personal Information)** , Personal information collected by NINEMSN from an individual may be disclosed to a specified third party client or partner of NINEMSN if the individual has consented to such disclosure. 

For example, if an individual provides personal information to NINEMSN when entering a competition sponsored by Ford on the NINEMSN Network, and the individual expressly checks a box prior to entering the competition which confirms they agree to have their personal information provided to Ford for the purpose of receiving marketing communications directly from Ford, NINEMSN will disclose this individual’s personal information to Ford for this purpose only. Any subsequent communications received by the individual from Ford will be subject to Ford’s privacy policy.

  3. _Disclosures required by law or NINEMSN policies._

We may access or disclose information about you, including the content of your communications, in order to: (a) comply with the law or respond to lawful requests or legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of NINEMSN or our customers, including the enforcement of our agreements or policies governing your use of the products or services; or (c) act on a good faith belief that such access or disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of NIENMSN employees, customers or the public.

We may also disclose personal information as part of a corporate transaction such as a merger or sale of shares or assets.

Otherwise, NINEMSN will only disclose personal information if you consent, or if it is otherwise permitted under the Privacy Act.

### OPTING IN AND UNSUBSCRIBING

### Opting In

At the point NINEMSN collects information from you, you may be asked to “opt in” to consent to us using or disclosing your personal information other than in accordance with this Privacy Policy or the Privacy Act. For example, you may be asked to opt-in to receive further information or communications from our advertisers and partners which do not fall into one of the categories described above.

### Opting Out / Unsubscribing

You will be given the opportunity to “opt out” from receiving communications from us or from third parties that send communications to you in accordance with this Privacy Policy. For example, you will be given the option to unsubscribe from newsletters, emails and other marketing or promotional material sent by us. You may “opt out” from receiving these communications by clicking on an unsubscribe link at the end of an email.

If you receive communications purporting to be connected with us or our services that you believe have been sent to you other than in accordance with this policy, or in breach of any law, please contact the NINEMSN Privacy Officer (contact details set out below).

### CO-BRANDED WEBSITES

NINEMSN has relationships with online business partners which permit users of the NINEMSN Network to link directly to websites operated by these partners. Some of these sites may be "co-branded" with the NINEMSN header and footer; however, these sites may not be owned, operated or maintained by or on NINEMSN’s behalf.

Before disclosing your personal information to any such co-branded sites, you should read the relevant privacy policies attaching to those sites. These co-branded sites may collect personal information from you that may be shared with NINEMSN. This Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner.

### LINKS TO THIRD PARTY WEBSITES FROM THE NINEMSN NETWORK

To the extent that the NINEMSN Network contains links to sites operated by third parties that are not co-branded sites and are not related to NINEMSN products, services or events or Microsoft Products (“ **Linked Websites** ”), the Linked Websites are not controlled or maintained by NINEMSN. We may collect personal information from Linked Websites in our role as a website portal. However, we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those companies. Before disclosing your personal information to Linked Websites, we advise you to examine their privacy policies. These Linked Sites may collect personal information from you that may be shared with NINEMSN. This Privacy Policy will apply to any personal information we obtain in this manner.

### SECURITY AND MANAGEMENT OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

NINEMSN understands that the security of your personal information is important. NINEMSN's policy is to ensure all our employees understand and take reasonable steps to keep personal information secure from unauthorised access, misuse, loss and interference.

We take physical, electronic and managerial steps to ensure that the personal information we hold is secure from unauthorised access, destruction, use, modification or disclosure. We only permit your details to be accessed by authorised personnel and we educate our staff about their responsibilities under the APPs. NINEMSN has also appointed a Privacy Officer to oversee NINEMSN’s management of personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Act.

Additionally, we take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information when we no longer need it. We also impose strict requirements of security and confidentially on all third parties as to how they store, handle and deal with personal information.

In striving to ensure that the security, integrity and privacy of personal information submitted to our site is maintained to the highest level, NINEMSN regularly reviews and updates its security measures in light of current technologies. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the internet or publically available website can be guaranteed to be totally secure and you need to be aware of this when using any websites on the NINEMSN Network.

Personal information collected on the NINEMSN Network may be stored and processed both in Australia and/or overseas countries including (but not limited to) the United States, Singapore and any other country in which NINEMSN or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. Some of NINEMSN’s third party contractors and service providers may perform some of their services overseas. For instance, a third party contractor may utilise a server hosted overseas as a method to send emails to NINEMSN customers. In all instances where this occurs, NINEMSN takes reasonable steps to ensure that third parties overseas handle all personal information in accordance with the APPs and this Privacy Policy.

### USE OF COOKIES

### What is a cookie?

A “cookie” is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web server. Cookies contain information that can later be read by a Web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.

### How we use cookies

The NINEMSN Network uses cookies to enable you to sign in to our services and to help personalise your online experience. One of the primary purposes of cookies is to store your preferences and other information on your computer in order to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalised content. The NINEMSN Network also use cookies as described in the **What kind of personal information does NINEMSN collect and how does NINEMSN collect it?** and **Display of Advertisements** sections of this Privacy Policy.

### Cookies and Windows Live IDs

When you sign in to a website using your Windows Live ID credentials, your unique ID number is stored in an encrypted cookie on your hard disk. This cookie allows you to move from page to page at the site without having to sign in again on each page. Cookies are also used to improve the sign in experience. For example, your e-mail address may be stored in a cookie that will remain on your computer after you sign out. This cookie allows your e-mail address to be pre-populated, so that you will only need to type your password the next time you sign in. If you are using a public computer or do not otherwise want this information to be stored, you can select the appropriate radio button on the sign-in page, and this cookie will not be used.

### Declining cookies

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to sign in or use other interactive features of the NINEMSN Network websites and services that depend on cookies, and some advertising preferences that are dependent on cookies may not be able to be respected. If you choose to accept cookies, you also have the ability to later delete cookies that you have accepted. If you chose to delete cookies, any settings and preferences, including advertising preferences, controlled by those cookies will be deleted and may need to be recreated.

### USE OF WEB BEACONS

### What is a web beacon?

The NINEMSN Network may contain electronic images known as “web beacons” - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that may be used to assist in delivering cookies on our sites and allow us to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services.

### How we use web-beacons

NINEMSN may include web beacons on all webpages on the NINEMSN Network in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. We may also employ web beacons from third parties in order to help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns or other operations of our websites. We prohibit web beacons on our websites from being used by third parties to collect or access your personal information.

Finally, we may work with other companies that advertise on the NINEMSN Network to place their Web beacons on NINEMSN sites in order to allow us to gather statistics and better target advertisements on the NINEMSN Network website that may result in a purchase or other action on the advertiser's site.

### NIELSEN//NETRATINGS

NINEMSN utilises the Nielsen//Netratings Australia auditing system on the NINEMSN Network. Nielsen//Netratings Australia collects data and uses cookies on the NINEMSN Network. For further information about Nielsen//Netratings Australia’s collection of data, use of cookies or to access Nielsen//Netratings Australia’s opt-out tool, please visit [nielsen-online.com](http://nielsen-online.com/)

### DISPLAY OF ADVERTISEMENTS

### Advertising on the NINEMSN Network

Many of the websites and online services we offer, as well as those of our partners, are supported by advertising. Through the Microsoft Advertising Platform, we may display advertisements on the NINEMSN Network (including the websites and mobile sites bearing the NINEMSN header and footer), and the sites of our advertising partners including the Mi9 third party ad network.

### How we personalise our advertising

When we display online advertisements to you, we will place one or more persistent cookies on your computer in order to recognise your computer each time we display an advertisement to you. The cookies we use for advertising have an expiry date of no more than two years. Because we may serve advertisements on many different websites, we are able to compile information over time about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw and/or clicked on the advertisements we display. We use this information to make predictions about your characteristics, interests or preferences and to display targeted advertisements that we believe may be of interest to you. We may also associate this information with your visit, purchase or other activity on participating advertiser’s websites in order to display targeted advertisements or to determine the effectiveness of the advertisements.

While we may use some of the information we collect in order to personalise the advertisements we show you, the Microsoft systems we use are designed to select advertisements based only on data that does not personally and directly identify you. For example, we may select the advertisements we display according to certain general interest categories or segments that we have inferred based on: 

  * demographic or interest data, including any you may have provided when creating a Windows Live ID account (e.g. age, postal code, gender), demographic or interest data acquired from other companies, and a general geographic location derived from your IP address;
  * the pages you view and links you click when using the NINEMSN Network and its advertising partners’ and clients' websites and services; 
  * the search terms you enter when using Microsoft Internet search services, such as Bing; and 
  * information about the users you most frequently interact with through social networking services.

### Your advertising choices

When we display personalised targeted ads, we take a number of steps designed to protect your privacy. For example, page views, clicks and search terms used for ad personalisation targeting are stored separately from your contact information or other data that directly identifies you (such as your name, e-mail address, etc.). We also give you the ability to control your preferences to receive this type of advertising via the NINEMSN opt out tool. For more information or to use our opt-out tool, you may visit [www.youronlinechoices.com.au](http://www.youronlinechoices.com.au/) which offers a single location to opt-out of ad targeting from member companies.

### Third party personalised advertising and YourOnlineChoices

Online advertisements on the NINEMSN Network are primarily served by Microsoft Advertising Platforms. We also serve advertising campaigns via other ad serving networks, to display advertisements on our sites. These companies currently include, but are not limited to Sizmek, Double Click, Facilitate and Eyewonder.

These companies may offer you a way to opt in or opt-out of ad targeting based on their cookies, and some of them are also signatories to the Australian Guidelines for Third Party Online Behavioural Advertising. You may find more information on these companies’ websites or by clicking [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.com.au/).

### HOW DOES NINEMSN TREAT SENSITIVE INFORMATION?

In referring to 'sensitive information' NINEMSN means information relating to a person's racial or ethnic origin, membership of political bodies, religions, trade unions or other professional or trade association, sexual preferences, criminal record and health information.

If you decide to provide NINEMSN with sensitive information, it is NINEMSN’s policy that this information will be used and disclosed only for the purpose for which it was provided or a directly related secondary purpose, unless you agree otherwise or use or disclosure of this information is allowed by law.

### ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION

Under the Privacy Act, you have the right to request access to the personal information which NINEMSN holds about you. There are some limitations to this right set out in the Privacy Act, which mean that we can refuse to provide you access to that information in limited circumstances, including where granting you access might have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of other individuals, if the request is frivolous or vexatious; or if the information relates to anticipated legal proceedings. If you wish to exercise your right under the Privacy Act to seek access to the personal information that NINEMSN holds about you, we ask that you contact NINEMSN using the contact details for the Privacy Officer set out below. We will assume (unless you tell us otherwise) that your request relates to our current records about you. These current records may include personal information about you which is included in our databases and in paper files (and which we may use on a day to day basis), or in tapes of programs which we have broadcast. 

Generally, NINEMSN will endeavour to acknowledge your request for access within 7 days, and to provide you with access within 30 days of the date of receipt of your request. We will notify you if we consider it will take longer than 30 days to endeavour to provide you with access. 

Therefore, if you seek access to records held by NINEMSN which are not current records, our Privacy Officer will need to contact you to discuss your request. If your access request to archived records is granted, please be aware that it may take a longer period of time to locate these records and that we may charge you for the cost of providing access. 

### CORRECTION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

NINEMSN endeavours to ensure that the personal information it holds is accurate, complete and up-to-date. 

You have the right to ask us to correct information about you which is inaccurate, incomplete, out of date, not relevant or misleading. NINEMSN is required to take such steps (if any) as are reasonable in the circumstances to correct the information. You are able to seek correction of your personal information that we hold about you, by notifying our Privacy Officer. NINEMSN’s policy is to respond to your request for correction within 30 days of receipt.

### Privacy Standards for NINEMSN Journalists 

As NINEMSN is a media organisation, the APPs do not apply to acts done or practices engaged in by NINEMSN in the course of journalism. This is because NINEMSN is committed to complying with the standards developed by the Australian Press Council in conjunction with its constituent members. The Press Council Privacy Standards are at Annexure A of this Privacy Policy and outline how journalists engaged by NINEMSN will handle personal information in the context of NINEMSN's journalism activities. 

### FURTHER INFORMATION ON PRIVACY

For more information about privacy issues in Australia, visit the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner's [website](http://www.privacy.gov.au/).

### HOW TO CONTACT THE NINEMSN PRIVACY OFFICER

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, complaints regarding how we handle your personal information or would like to make an access request, please contact NINEMSN by writing to Privacy Officer, NINEMSN Pty Limited, Locked Bag H50, Australia Square Sydney NSW 1215 or via e-mail [privacyofficer@mi9.com.au](mailto:privacyofficer@mi9.com.au). All complaints received will be assessed by the Privacy Officer and all reasonable steps (if any) will be taken to remedy the complaint. NINEMSN will endeavour to respond to your complaint within 30 days of receipt of the complaint by NINEMSN’S Privacy Officer.

NINEMSN Pty Limited is an Mi9 company.

### ANNEXURE A - AUSTRALIAN PRESS COUNCIL PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

### Privacy Principle 1: Collection of personal information

In gathering news, journalists should seek personal information only in the public interest. In doing so, journalists should not unduly intrude on the privacy of individuals and should show respect for the dignity and sensitivity of people encountered in the course of gathering news.

In accordance with Principle 5 of the Council's Statement of Principles, news obtained by unfair or dishonest means should not be published unless there is an overriding public interest. Generally, journalists should identify themselves as such. However, journalists and photographers may at times need to operate surreptitiously to expose crime, significantly anti-social conduct, public deception or some other matter in the public interest.

Public figures necessarily sacrifice their right to privacy, where public scrutiny is in the public interest. However, public figures do not forfeit their right to privacy altogether. Intrusion into their right to privacy must be related to their public duties or activities.

### Privacy Principle 2: Use and disclosure of personal information

Personal information gathered by journalists and photographers should only be used for the purpose for which it was intended. A person who supplies personal information should have a reasonable expectation that it will be used for the purpose for which it was collected.

Some personal information, such as addresses or other identifying details, may enable others to intrude on the privacy and safety of individuals who are the subject of news coverage, and their families. To the extent lawful and practicable, a media organisation should only disclose sufficient personal information to identify the persons being reported in the news, so that these risks can be reasonably avoided.

### Privacy Principle 3: Quality of personal information

A media organisation should take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it collects is accurate, complete and up-to-date.

### Privacy Principle 4: Security of personal information

A media organisation should take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information it holds is protected from misuse, loss, or unauthorised access.

### Privacy Principle 5: Anonymity of sources

All persons who provide information to media organisations are entitled to seek anonymity. The identity of confidential sources should not be revealed, and where it is lawful and practicable, a media organisation should ensure that any personal information which it maintains derived from such sources does not identify the source.

### Privacy Principle 6: Correction, fairness and balance

In accordance with Principle 3 of the Council's Statement of Principles, where individuals are a major focus of news reports or commentary, the publication should ensure fairness and balance in the original article. Failing that, the media organisation should provide a reasonable and swift opportunity for a balancing response in the appropriate section of the publication.

A media organisation should make amends for publishing any personal information that is found to be harmfully inaccurate, in accordance with Principle 2 of the Council's Statement of Principles. The media organisation should also take steps to correct any of its records containing that personal information, so as to avoid a harmful inaccuracy being repeated.

### Privacy Principle 7: Sensitive personal information

In accordance with Principle 8 of the Council's Statement of Principles, media organisations should not place any gratuitous emphasis on the categories of sensitive personal information listed in Principle 8, except where it is relevant and in the public interest to report and express opinions in these areas. Members of the public caught up in newsworthy events should not be exploited. A victim or bereaved person has the right to refuse or terminate an interview or photographic session at any time.

Unless otherwise restricted by law or court order, open court hearings are matters of public record and can be reported by the press. Such reports need to be fair and balanced. They should not identify relatives or friends of people accused or convicted of crime unless the reference to them is necessary for the full, fair and accurate reporting of the crime or subsequent legal proceedings.
